Preliminary Guide to the I. Richard Savage Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Series I, 1955-1989; 27 linear feet (23 boxes)
  - Published Papers
    - "Stopping Time of a Rank-Order SPRT Based on Lehmann Alternatives"; with Sethuraman, J., 1966 (Box 18)
    - "Publications of Frank Wilcoxon (1892-1965)"; with Karas, James, 1967 (Box 18)
    - "Surveillance Problems: Two-Dimensional with Continuous Surveillance"; with Antelman, Gordon R., and Russell, C. Bradley, 1967 (Box 18)
    - "The Information in a Rank-Order and the Stopping Time of Some Associated SPRT's"; with Berk, Robert H., 1968 (Box 18)
    - Statistics: Uncertainty and Behavior, 1967-1968
      - Addenda (Box 18)
      - Copyright and Contract (Box 18)
      - Financial (Box 18)
      - General correspondence (Box 18)
      - Permissions (Box 18)
      - Reviews (Box 18)
    - "Nonparametric Statistics: The Field"; in International Encyclopedia of Social Sciences, 1968 (Box 18)
    - "A Branching Process Without Rebranching"; with Shimi, I. N., 1969 (Box 18)
    - "Monotonicity of Rank Order Likelihood Ratio"; with Saxena, K. M. Lal, 1969 (Box 18)
    - "Nonparametric Statistics: A Personal Review", 1969 (Box 18)
    - "Nonparametric Statistics in Endocrinology", 1970 (Box 18)
    - Mathematical Sciences and Social Sciences; ed. by Savage, 1970 (Box 18)
    - "Random Wear Models in Reliability Theory"; with Reynolds, David S., 1971 (Box 18)
    - Order Statistics, by Herbert A. David: published review, 1971 (Box 18)
    - Biometrika Tables for Statisticians, by E. S. Pearson and H. O. Hartley: published review, 1976 (?) (Box 18)
    - The Significance Test Controversy - A Reader, ed. by Denton E. Morrison and Ramon E. Henkel: published review, 1972 (Box 18)
    - "Asymptotic Distribution of the Log Likelihood Ratio Based on Ranks in the Two-Sample Problem"; with Sethuraman, J., 1972 (Box 18)
    - Incomplete Contingency Tables, 1973 (Box 18)
    - Index-Guide to Vols. 1-31 of the ANNALS OF MATHEMATICAL STATISTICS; with Greenwood, J. A., and Olkin, I., 1973?
      - Correspondence on Olkin Index; Citation trace letters (Box 18)
      - Institute of Mathematical Sciences (IMS)
        - 1959 (Box 18)
        - 1960 (Box 18)
        - 1961 (Box 18)
        - Finances (Box 18)
    - "Large-Sample Properties of Log-Likelihood Ratios of Rank Orders in the Two-Sample Problem"; with Sethuraman, J., 1973 (Box 18)
    - "Sociology Wants Mathematics", 1973 (Box 18)
    - Statistics: A Guide to the Unknown, ed. by Judith M. Tanur, Frederick Mosteller, et al .: published review, 1974 (Box 18)
    - Bulletin of IMS:, "Style" (Box 18)
    - "Source of Evaluations Reformulated and Analyzed"; with Webster, Murray Jr., [1973?] (Box 19)
    - Technical Paper No. 32: "Review of U. s. Bureau of the Census " Standards for Discussion and Presentation of Errors in Data, 1974 (Box 19)
    - "Cost-Benefit Analysis of Demographic Data", 1975 (Box 19)
    - Introduction to Multiregional Mathematical Demography, by Andrei Rogers: published review, 1975 (Box 19)
    - Race Differences in Intelligence, by John C. Loehlin, Gardner Lindzey, and J. N. Spuhler: published review, 1975 (Box 19)
    - "Statistical Studies in Prediction of Attendance for a University," with Brown, Byron Jr.; in Analytical Models in Educational Planning and Administration (editor?), 1975 (Box 19)
    - "Setting Statistical Priorities", 1976 (Box 19)
    - "Thoughts on the Editorial Process", 1976 (Box 19)
    - A Mathematical Theory of Evidence, by Glen Shafer: published review, 1976 (Box 19)
    - Exchanges of statisticians, 1978 (Box 19)
    - "A Statistician's Search for Oil", 1978 (Box 19)
    - "Young Chains and Rank Orders"; with Narayana, T. V., and Saxena, K. M. Lal, 1978-1979 (Box 19)
    - "The Role of Applications in the Undergraduate Mathematics Curriculum," by the Ad hoc Committee on Applied Mathematics Training, National Research Council (Savage was on the committee), 1978-1979 (Box 19)
    - Developments in Statistics, Vol. I., ed. by Paruchuri R. Krishnaiah: published review, 1979 (Box 19)
    - "Dirichlet Processes Produce Discrete Measures: An Elementary Proof"; with Robert H. Berk, 1979 (Box 19)
    - Statistical Policy working Paper 1: Report on Statistics for Allocation of Funds, by Subcommittee on Statistics for Allocation of Funds, U. S. Department of Commerce: published review, 1980 (Box 20)
    - "Modifying Census Counts"(3 copies), 1980 (Box 20)
    - "Reprinted Articles in Statistics and Probability Theory: A Bibliography"; with Leysieffer, Frederick W., and Sylvester, Richard J., 1980 (Box 20)
    - "Statistical Exercise", 1980 (Box 20)
    - "On Not Being Rational", 1980 (Box 20)
    - Panel on Testing of Handicapped People (Savage a member), 1982 (Box 20)
    - "Who Counts", 1982 (Box 20)
    - "Lehmann Alternatives", 1980-1983 (Box 20)
    - Contributions to Statistics, by William G. Cochran: published review, 1983 (Box 20)
    - "Some Problems with Social Statistical Systems", 1984 (Box 20)
    - "Federal Statistics and National Needs," by "Conference on Federal Statistics and National Needs," Congressional Research Service (transcript of conference; Savage a participant), 1984 (Box 20)
    - "Hard - Soft Problems", 1985 (Box 20)
    - Bicentennial Census: New Directions for Methodology in 1990, ed. by Constance F. Citro, Michael L. Cohen, .: published review, 1986 (Box 20)
    - "Random Variables"; published in The New Palgrave, 1987 (Box 20)
    - Savage, Leonard J. ("Jimmie"): biography by I. R. Savage, 1987 (Box 20)
    - "Random Variables", 1987 (Box 20)
  - Slides
    - Martha (Box 20)
    - Miscellaneous (2 envelopes) (Box 20)
  - Prediction Study: reports from University of Minnesota, Minneapolis Campus Planning Committee, Enrollment Subcommittee, Research Staff (Savage on Research Staff: report is on predicting future enrollments) (Box 21)
  - Reprints (of Savage writings), 1951-1954 (Box 21)
  - Reprints, 1953-1955 (Box 21)
  - Reprints, 1952-1953 (Box 21)
  - Datebooks: personal and business notes (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, 1975-1979 (Box 23)
  - Correspondence, 1980, 1989-1991 (Box 23)
  - Datebook, 1957-1979 (Box 23)
  - Notebooks 1 - 3, 1979 (Box 23)
  - "On the Occasion of His Sixtieth Birthday", 1985 October 26 (Box 23)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 23)
  - Publications, 1964-1975: bound volume of reprints (Box 23)
  - R. A. Fisher Award, 1983 (Box 23)
  - Reprints, 1953-1987 (Box 23)
  - Reviews by I. R. Savage, 1953-1965 (Box 23)
  - Reviews by I. R. Savage, 1966-1969 (Box 23)
  - Reviews by I. R. Savage, 1970-1979 (Box 23)
  - Reviews by I. R. Savage, 1980-1984 (Box 23)
  - Books
    - Ability Testing of Handicapped People: Dilemma for Government, Science, and the Public, 1982 (Box 23)
    - Bibliography of Nonparametric Statistics, by I. R. Savage (2), 1962 (Box 23)
    - "Doodles by Mathematicians and Others," tribute to Leon W. Cohen, 1972 June 8 (Box 23)
    - Rank Order Statistics, by I. R. Savage (2), undated (Box 23)
    - Setting Statistical Priorities, Panel on Methodology for Statistical Priorities of the Committee on National Statistics, I. R. Savage, chairman (2 copies), 1976 (Box 23)
    - Statistics: Uncertainty and Behavior, by I. R. Savage, 1968 (Box 23)
    - Statistics 210A, Installment #1, by David Pollard, 1984 (Box 23)
- Additional Material, 1995; Accession 1996-M-005
  - "Rolling Around" [autobiographical typescript], 1995 (Box 1, Folder 1-3)
- Additional Material, Accession 2001-M-075
  - Correspondence
    - Fischer, R. A. to Churchill Eisenhart re I. Richard Savage, 1952 September 22 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Haldane, J. B. S. to I. Richard Savage, 1953 Dec 9 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Statistics and Public Policy, by Bruce D. Spencer ["…inspired by the work of I. Richard Savage"], 1997 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "A Conversation with I. Richard Savage," Statistical Science ,14:1, 1999 February (Box 1, Folder 4)